[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "One whose attitude is ‘eat, drink and be merry’ is",
    "options": ["materialistic", "epicurean", "cynic", "stoic"],
    "answer": "epicurean"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "‘Call me if you have any problems regarding your work.’ Here ‘regarding’ is a/an-",
    "options": ["gerund", "apposition", "preposition", "conjunction"],
    "answer": "preposition"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "‘Come on, it’s time to go home.’ Here ‘home’ is a/an-",
    "options": ["noun", "verb", "adjective", "adverb"],
    "answer": "adverb"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "‘Who’s that?’ In this sentence ‘that’ is a/an-",
    "options": ["pronoun", "conjunction", "adjective", "adverb"],
    "answer": "pronoun"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What is the noun form of the word ‘know’?",
    "options": ["Knowing", "knowledge", "knowledgeable", "known"],
    "answer": "knowledge"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "‘I shall help you provided you obey me.’ Here the underlined word is a/an-",
    "options": ["adverb", "adjective", "conjunction", "verb"],
    "answer": "conjunction"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "‘Huffing and puffing, we arrived at the classroom door with only seven seconds to spare.’ In this sentence the verb ‘arrived’ is-",
    "options": ["intransitive", "transitive", "causative", "defective"],
    "answer": "intransitive"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which one of the following is a common gender?",
    "options": ["king", "sovereign", "emperor", "queen"],
    "answer": "sovereign"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Identify the word that can be used as both singular and plural:",
    "options": ["wood", "issue", "fish", "light"],
    "answer": "fish"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "‘The old man was tired of walking’. Here ‘walking’ is a/an-",
    "options": ["present participle", "adjective", "common noun", "gerund"],
    "answer": "gerund"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "‘I will not let you go.’ In this sentence ‘go’ is a/an-",
    "options": ["infinitive", "gerund", "participle", "verbal noun"],
    "answer": "infinitive"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "When Ushashi entered __ the room everybody stopped talking.",
    "options": ["into", "in", "to", "no preposition required"],
    "answer": "no preposition required"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Which ‘but’ is a preposition?",
    "options": [
      "It is but right to admit our faults.",
      "What can we do but sit and wait?",
      "We tried hard, but did not succeed.",
      "There is no one but likes him."
    ],
    "answer": "What can we do but sit and wait?"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "‘Give somebody a piece of your mind’ means to-",
    "options": [
      "tell someone that you are very angry with them.",
      "say exactly what you feel or think",
      "return or to help somebody return to a normal situation",
      "give somebody mental peace."
    ],
    "answer": "tell someone that you are very angry with them."
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "‘ To win a prize is my ambition.’ The underlined part of the sentence is a/an-",
    "options": [
      "adjective phrase",
      "noun phrase",
      "adverb phrase",
      "conjunctional phrase"
    ],
    "answer": "noun phrase"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Choose the word opposite in meaning to ‘terse’.",
    "options": ["concise", "detailed", "expressive", "descriptive"],
    "answer": "detailed"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Identify the correct spelling:",
    "options": ["questionaire", "questionoir", "questionnaire", "questionair"],
    "answer": "questionnaire"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Find out the correct passive form of the sentence ‘Who taught you French?’",
    "options": [
      "By whom you were taught French?",
      "By whom French was taught you?",
      "French was taught you by whom?",
      "By whom were you taught French?"
    ],
    "answer": "By whom were you taught French?"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Select the correct comparative form of the sentence ‘A string of pearls was not so bright as her teeth.’",
    "options": [
      "Her teeth was more brighter than a string of pearls.",
      "Her teeth were brighter than a string of pearls",
      "A string of pearls was brighter than her teeth",
      "A string of pearls were very bright than her teeth"
    ],
    "answer": "Her teeth were brighter than a string of pearls"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Which one is a correct sentence?",
    "options": [
      "The doctor found my pulse.",
      "The doctor took my pulse",
      "The doctor examined my pulse",
      "The doctor say my pulse"
    ],
    "answer": "The doctor took my pulse"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "‘Was this the face that launch’d a thousand ships, And burnt the topless towers of Ilium?’ Who speaks the famous lines?",
    "options": ["Caesar", "Antony", "Faustus", "Romeo"],
    "answer": "Faustus"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "The Character ‘Alfred Doolittle’ is taken from Shaw’s play titled-",
    "options": [
      "Pygmalion",
      "Man and Superman",
      "The Doctor’s Dilemma",
      "Mrs. Warren’s Profession"
    ],
    "answer": "Pygmalion"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "In Shakespeare’s play Hamlet, Hamlet was prince of-",
    "options": ["Norway", "Britain", "Denmark", "France"],
    "answer": "Denmark"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "The poem ‘The Love Song of J. Alfred Prufrock’ is written by-",
    "options": ["W. B. Yeats", "T.S. Eliot", "Walter Scott", "Robert Browning"],
    "answer": "T.S. Eliot"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Who is the author of the first scientific romance ‘The Time Machine’?",
    "options": ["H.G. Wells", "Samuel Butler", "Henry James", "George Moore"],
    "answer": "H.G. Wells"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Adela Quested and Mrs. Moore are characters from the novel-",
    "options": [
      "David Copperfield",
      "The Return of the Native",
      "A passage to India",
      "Adam Bede"
    ],
    "answer": "A passage to India"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "‘Shylock’ is a character in the play-",
    "options": [
      "Twelfth Night",
      "The Merchant of Venice",
      "Romeo and Juliet",
      "Measure for Measure"
    ],
    "answer": "The Merchant of Venice"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "‘Why, then, ‘tis none to you, for there is nothing either good or bad, but thinking makes it so.’ This extract is taken from the drama-",
    "options": ["King Lear", "Macbeth", "As You Like It", "Hamlet"],
    "answer": "Hamlet"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "‘Made weak by time and fate, but strong in will ‘To strive, to seek, to find, and not to yield’ is taken from the poem written by-",
    "options": [
      "Robert Browning",
      "Matthew Arnold",
      "Alfred Tennyson",
      "Lord Byron"
    ],
    "answer": "Alfred Tennyson"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "‘Pip’ is the protagonist in Charles Dickens’ novel-",
    "options": [
      "A Christmas Carol",
      "A Tale of Two Cities",
      "Oliver Twist",
      "Great Expectations"
    ],
    "answer": "Great Expectations"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "‘Lady Chatterleyy’s Lover’ was written by the author of-",
    "options": ["Lord Jim", "The Rainbow", "Ulyesses", "A Passage to India"],
    "answer": "The Rainbow"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "‘Vanity Fair’ is a novel written by-",
    "options": [
      "D. H. Lawrence",
      "William Makepeace Thackeray",
      "Joesph Conrad",
      "Virgina Woolf"
    ],
    "answer": "William Makepeace Thackeray"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Who is not a romantic poet?",
    "options": ["P. B. Shelley", "S.T. Coleridge", "John Keats", "T.S. Eliot"],
    "answer": "T.S. Eliot"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "The play ‘The Birthday Party’ is written by-",
    "options": [
      "Samuel Beckett",
      "Henry Livings",
      "Harold Pinter",
      "Arthur Miller"
    ],
    "answer": "Harold Pinter"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "‘Time held me green and dying Though I sang in my chains like the sea.’ These lines have been quoted from Dylan Thomas’ Poem-",
    "options": ["The Flower", "Fern Hill", "By Fire", "After the Funeral"],
    "answer": "Fern Hill"
  }
]
